Please welcome AI researcher and founding member of openai Andre
Play karpathy
Hi everyone
I'm happy to
Tell you about
And more generally about
The rapidly growing
Ecosystem of large
Two
In the first part I would like to tell you about how we train
And then in the second part
We are going to take a look at how we can use these assistance effectively for your
Give me a recipe
So rapidly evolving
Piece by piece
But roughly speaking we have four major stages
Reinforcement learning
We have a data set that is the powers that stage
We have an algorithm that for our purposes will be a
Objective
And over for training neural network
And then there's some notes on the bottom
Turn on the computational work basically happens this is 99% of the training
Compute time
And also flops
And so this is where we are dealing with internet scale data sets
With thousands of gpus in the supercomputer
And also
The other three stages are fine-tuning stages
That are much more along the lines of
Hours or days
To achieve a base model
Here's an example of what we call a data mixture
That comes from this
I was really by met
And then some high-quality data sets as well so for example GitHub
Wikipedia books archive Stock Exchange and so on
These are all mixed up together and then they are sampled According to some given proportions
And that
The training set for the neural
We need to go through one more pre-processing step and that is tokenization
Sequences of integ
Now this is a lossless
That's kind of translation between pieces of text and tokens and integers
And there are a number of algorithms for the stage
And groups them into tokens
And then this is the raw into your sequence that will actually feed into a Transformer
Examples for hyperparameters that govern the
We did not release too much information about how it was trained and so on so I'm using gpt-3 numbers but
83 years of course a little bit old by now
About 3 years ago
Obama is a fairly recent
The vocabulary size is usually a couple 10,000 tokens
The maximum number of integers
The next integer in a
You can see that roughly the number of parameters is say 65 billion for llama
Parameters
Llama is a significantly more powerful model
And intuitively
Play that's because the model is trained for significantly longer in this case 1.4 trillion tokens instead of just $300 billion
Parameters that
Rough hyperparameters that typically go into specifying the Transformer neural network
Dimension size number of layers and so on
And on the bottom I'm showing some training at the par
Meta used 2000 gpus
A training and
So we have these arrays that will feed into the Transformer
Being the maximum contact Len
The contact lens so this could be $2,406
Tokens
And so here I have a few examples of documents and then I stretch them out into
Into this in
Now we're going to feed
All of these numbers into Transformer
And let me let me
Focus on a single particular cell but the same thing will happen at every every cell in this diagram
The green cell
It's going to take a look at all of the tokens before it so all of the tokens in yellow
And we're going to feed that entire contact into the Transformer neural network
End of the Transformer is going to try to predict the next token in the sequence in this case in red
Now the Transformer I don't have too much time to unfortunately go into the full details of this neural network architecture
Neural net
For our purposes and it's got
Several 10 billion parameters typically or something like that
Predicted distributions for every single one of these cells
Vocabulary size
What's 50000257 tokens
Then we're going to have that many numbers
Because we need to specify a probability distribution
For what
Now in the specific example for the specific cell
513 will come next
And so we can use this as a source of supervision to update our Transformers
What token comes next in a
This is actually coming from a New York Times and they trained a small GPT on Shakespeare
Now in the beginning
At initialization
Longer and longer
You are getting more and more coherent and consistent
Sort of a samples from the model
You are pred
What comes next
And you can basically
Sample
Commas and so on
And so we're making more and more consistent predictions over time
These are the kinds of flaws that you're looking at when you're doing model pre-training effectively we're looking at the loss function
It's giving a higher probability to
Now what are we going to do with this model once we've trained it after a
Well the first thing that we noticed
Read the field
Is
Arbitrary Downstream task in my painter
Classification
The app
Used to be
You collect a bunch of positives and negatives and then you train some kind of an MLP model for for that
But the new approach is
And then you can only you may only have a few examples
And the reason for this is that basically the Transformer is for
Because
Of
That actually even better than fine tuning
Are these fake
And then
And so this is an example of
Now since then we've seen an entire evolutionary tree of Base models that everyone has trained
Not all of these models are available
For example the gp4 base model was never released
Base model
Under the name da Vinci
But currently the best available base model probably is
Baseballs are not
They don't want to answer
We don't want to make answers to your questions
They just want to complete document
So if you tell them write a poem about the brain cheese
It will just
That that is more likely to work so as an example here's a poem about bread and cheese
You can even
Bass models into being assistance
And and their exchanging sort of
And then
And the base model will sort of like
A condition itself into being
I like a helpful assistant
So instead we have a different path to make
Document
We are going to collect
Small but high quality data
To gather data of the form
And ideal response
Obviously QA prompt response
And you can actually deploy these models and they are actual assistants and they work to some extent
Let me show you what an example demonstration might look like
Here's some random prompt
Can you write a short introduction about the relevance of the term Monopoly
Or something like that
And then the contractor also writes out an ideal response
Extensive labeling documentation
And they're being asked to be
Now you can actually
Continue the pipeline from here on
And go into rlhs reinforcement learning from Human feedback
That consists of both reward modeling and reinforcement learning
Is we're not going to shift our data collection to be off the form of comparisons
I have the same prompt identical prompt on the top
The assistant to write a program or function
Add
And we create multiple completions
And then we ask people to rank these completions
So if you stare at this for a while and by the way these are very difficult things to do to compare some of these predictions
Paris
Classification on all the possible pairs
Identical across all three rows here
Read
How good that completion is
About the quality of each completion
And then once it makes a guess for every one of them
Reward predictions are consistent
Put the ground truth coming from the comparisons from all these contractors
We can't deploy this because this is not very useful as an assistant by itself
Reinforcement learning stage that follows
Arbitrary completion for any given prom
A large collection of prompts
And now we do reversible learning with respect to the reward model
We would take a single prompt
And we read off the reward
Loss function but
And we are weighing
In the first row the reward model said
Add that this is a fairly high-scoring completion
On the first row are going to get reinforced
And they're going to get higher probabilities
For the future
-1.2
Is going to get a slightly higher probability for the future
Many batches
And it's basically all of them
So that's how we train that's what the rhf pipeline
Now and then at the end you got a model that you could deploy and so is an example
Chachi Patty is an arch of model
Models
And that's kind of like the state of
Now why would you want to do our life
Not that exciting is that it just works better so this comes from the instructor GPT paper
According to these experiments a while ago now
This PPO models are roh
And we see that we are basically just preferred
Comparisons
Tokens that come from our relative models
And so it just works better
You might ask why
Why does it work better
Agreed on
One one reason potentially
And it has to do with the asymmetry between how easy computationally it is to compare
Versus Jenner
So let's take an example of generating a Haik
Paper clips
If you're a contractor trying to get a train data
Then imagine being a contractor collecting basically data for the sft stage
How are you supposed to create a nice haiku for a paperclip you might just not be very good at that
Are
Strictly an improvement on the base models in
So for example one one kind of place where I still prefer to use a base model
Is in a setup where
You basically
Have any things and you want to
YouTube generate more things like it
I want to generate cool Pokemon names
Pokemon names and I asked the base model to complete the document
And this is kind of tasks that I think base model would be good at because it still has lots of entropy and I'll give you lots of diverse
There's a team at Berkeley that ranked
A lot of the available assistant models
And give them basically ELO ratings
Followed by
Like the kuna koala Etc
And the first
Okay so
Now I'm going to switch gears and let's look at how we can best
App
And something of a concrete example
Let's say that you are working on an article or a blog post
California's population is 53 times that of Alaska so for some reason you want to compare the populations of these
Think about
The rich internal monologue
Now I know that I probably don't know
What's the population of the top of my head
And I go to Wikipedia and I look up
Now I know that I should divide the two
39.2 * 0.74 is very unlikely to succeed
That's not the kind of thing that I can do in my head
And then maybe I do some reflection and Sanity checks in my brain
Well that's quite quite a large fraction but then California has the most popular state
So then I have all the information I might need
California has 53x times greater and then I think to myself
Inspecting what I'm writing
And judging whether it looks good or not
And then maybe I'm happy with what comes out
Under the hood in terms of your internal monologue when you create sentences like this
What does a sentence like this look like when we are training
Is roughly the same amount of computational work for each token
To imitate
But of course
In our final artifacts in the data sets that we create and then eventually fee to all alarm
All that internal dialogue
And unlike
Every one of them
And so you can't expect it to actually like
So they don't know what they don't know like
They don't reflect
What in the loop
They just
They don't have separate inner monologue streams in their head right they're evaluating what's happening
Cognitive advantages I would say
And they also I think have a relatively large and perfect working mem
Is immediately available to the Transformer through its internal self-attention mechanism
Prompting is just making up
For this sort of cognitive
What's between these two
What are brains here and llm
Require reasoning
Transformer a very complicated question and expect it to get the answer in a single token
This is not enough time for it
These Transformers need Tok
You may for example have a few short prompt that shows the Transformer that it should like show its work when it's answering
When is Samsung question
Transformer will imitate
And it will just end up
Working out better
In terms of its evaluation
This kind of behavior from the Transformer
Because this condition is the transformer into a sort of like showing its work
And so it's more likely to succeed as a result because it's making
Consistency
We saw that we had the ability to start writing
And and maybe
Select the one that worked best
In these kinds of approaches you may sample not just once but you may sample multiple times
What's for finding the ones that are good
Majority vote or something like that
Predict the next token
Just like you they can get un
In terms of reasoning
Tell me if they even know that the sequence is not going to work out
Try to find
Say you asked the model to generate a poem that does not rhyme
But without you prompting it
Like it doesn't know
It doesn't know to revisit
Get it to check
So you might be familiar with the system one system to thinking for humans
Automatic process
Deliberate
And entry of
The authors of this paper proposed maintaining multiple completions
For any given prompt
If that makes sense
And so a lot of people are like really playing around with kind of
Trump engineering
Now one thing I would like to note here is that this is not just a
This is actually
Because you don't you actually have to maintain multiple problems and you also have to do some research algorithm here
Python glucose and individual prompts
Imitating humans
But in addition to this policy
It also does Monte Carlo tree
Number of possibilities in its head and evaluate all of them and only keep the ones that work well and so I think this is kind of
Sound of an equivalent of alphago
People are starting to like really explore
Stringing together many problems
So on the right
I have an example from this paper called react
Were the structure
As a sequence of
Fault action observation thought action observation
In these actions the model is also allowed to to
On the left
I have an example of Auto GPT
And I think but I think I still find it kind of inspirationally interesting
It's a project that allows an llm to sort of keep task
List and continue to recursively break break down tasks
So that's kind of like giving our model system to thinking
Psychological Quirk of all alarms
Is that
Elements don't want to succeed
They want to imitate
You want
And you should ask for
So what I mean by that is
When Transformers are trained
There can be an entire spectrum of performance qualities in their training
It's they tried various prompts
To be sure we have the right answer
Quality Solutions
Basically don't feel free to ask for a strong solution
Say something like you are leading expert on this topic
Etc
You might be out of date of distribution
Or even worse you could be in data distribution for some like sci-fi stuff and it will start to like take out some Sapphire
I think
Next
As we saw when we are trying to solve problems
Computationally
You want to do the same potential with your flms
In particular
We may want to give them
Calculator
The
What should you do search
Transformers by default may not know
You are not very good at
Add mental arithmetic
Whenever you need to do very large number of addition multiplication or whatever instead use this calculator
Combination Etc ET
Just like you
You and I
Next stop I think something that is very interesting is
We went from a world
That was retrieval only
All the way the pendulum has swung to The Other Extreme where its memory only in
Off these retrieval augmented models
Transformer is it's working memory
Because it can immediately access all that memory
And so I think a lot of people are really interested in
Basically
Retrieval augment to generation
Data connector to lots of different types of data
And you can you can make it
You take relevant documents
You embed all of them
And you basically get embedding vectors that represent the data
And you fetch
Books that might be relevant to your
You can do everything from your memory and Transformers have very large and extensive memory
Going back to documentation of a library to look something up
Transformers definitely when I do that too
Some documentation of a library works but it's much better to look it up
This is basically
Techniques
Forcing a certain template in the outputs of LL
And here we are enforcing that the output from the llm will be Json
And this will actually
Guaranteed that the output will take on this form because they go in and they mess with the probabilities of all the different tokens that come out of the Transformer
And then you can enforce additional restrictions on
So this might be really helpful
I also wanted to say a few words about fine-tuning
It is the case that you can get really far with prompt engineering
But it's also possible to think about fine-tuning your
Now find tuning models that means that you are actually going to change the weights of the model
It is becoming a lot more accessible to do this in practice
Of a number of techniques that have been developed and have libraries for
Make sure that you're only Trent you're only training small
What's pieces of your model
And some pieces of it are allowed to change
You can use an inference for computing those parts
Because you're not going to be updated by gradient descent
And in addition we have a number of Open Source high-quality based models
What's currently as I mentioned I think
Something to keep in mind is that
Is a lot more technically involved
It requires a lot more I think technical expertise to do
It requires
What's human data contractors for data sets and or synthetic data pipelines that can be pretty complicated
This will definitely slow down your iteration cycle by a lot
Achievable
Even much harder to get to work
And so I would probably not advised that someone just tries to roll their own knowledge of implementation these things are pretty unstable
Not something that is I think very beginner friendly right now
Default recommendations
Right now
Number one achieve your top performance
What's the number to optimize your performance in that order
Number one the best performance will currently come from GT4 model
It is the most capable of by far
Use prompts that are very detailed
Relevant information and instructions
If they can't email you back
Do not possess those
So make sure to
Think through the psychology of the llm almost in Cedar prompts to that
Retrieve and add any relevant contacts and information to these prompts
List some of them have highlighted in the slides above
And I would just advise you to look for prompt engineer
There's a lot to cover there
Experiment with few shop examples
What does refers to is you don't just want to tell you want to show
Whenever it's possible
Experimental tools and plugins to offload a tasks that are difficult for llms natively
Finally if you think you've squeezed out prompt engineering
Which I think you should stick with for a while
Look at some
But expect this to be a lot more slower involved
A bit better than SRT if you can get it to work but
Just try to explore lower capacity models
Or shorter prompt
Also wanted
Play say a few words about the use cases in which I think flms are currently well suited for
So in particular note that there's a large number of limitations to flms today
Any fabricate hallucinate information
They may struggle an entire classes of applications
So they might not know any information about
Coming out
Including prompt injection jailbreak attacks data poisoning attacks and so
Use all alarms in low
Combine them with always with human oversight
Use them as a source of inspiration and suggestions
And
So I wanted to close by saying that GT4 is an amazing artifact I'm very thankful that it exists
And it's it's beautiful it has a ton of knowledge across so many areas
And so on
Ecosystem of everything else that is being built incorporated into into the ecosystem
Is accessible at your fingertips
To ask GPT for a question
In this case I said can you say something to inspire the audience of Microsoft Bill 2023
And I just punched this into Python and verbatim
And by the way I did not know that they used the strict in the Keynote
Butt but it is really good at this it says
Microsoft build
Welcome to the Gathering of Brilliant Minds like no other
You are The Architects of the future
The Visionaries molding the digital realm in which Humanity thrives
Embrace the Limitless possibilities of techn
Remarkable
Get ready to unleash your creativity canvas the unknown
Listen to reality
Your Journey Begins