All right well this is a 650 Tech talk thank you all so much for coming so about a week ago we circulated the Google form
How warm is you might have seen at 10:52 a.m. and by like 11:52 a.m. we had a hundred is which I think is
Play sort of Testament to just how much interest there is in this world of AI and open Ai and GPT Chachi PT in the like
And in fact if you're sort of generally familiar with what everyone's talking about but you haven't tried it yourself like this is the URL
What you can try out this tool that you've probably heard about chat GPT
You can sign up for a free account there and start tinkering with what everyone else has been tinkering with and then if you're more of the app mind
Has its own low-level apis
Actions and services that have been built on top of these Technologies and we're so happy today to be joined by our friends from McGill
Spell university and steamship
Are seal and Ted from you here in just a moment to speak to us about how they are making it easier to build
To deploy to share applications using some of these very same technology so are things to them for hosting today our friends
Did Clemson Jenny Lee an alumna who's here with us today but without further Ado allow me to turn things over to Ted and sill and pizza will be served shortly
Play after 1:00 p.m. outside
Thanks a lot
Hey everybody it's great to be here I think we've got a really good talk for you today still going to provide some res
Research grounding into how it all works what's going inside
The brain of GPT as well as other language models
And then I'll show you some examples that we're seeing on the ground of how people are building apps and what apps tend to work in the real world
So our perspective is we're building AWS for AI app so we get to talk to a lot of the makers who are building and deploying their apps
And through that see both the experimental end of the spectrum
And also see what kinds of apps are getting pushed out there and turned into companies turned into side projects
We did a cool
A hackathon yesterday many things to Neiman to David Manning cs50 for helping us put all of
Put this together to Harvard for hosting it
And there were two sessions lots of folks built things if you go to
Steamship dot calm slash hackathon you'll find a lot of guides a lot of projects that people build and you can follow along we have a
Text guide as well just as a quick plug for that
If you want to do it remotely or on your own
To tee up so we're going to talk about basically two things today that I hope you walk away with
What is GPT and how is it working
You can get a good sense of what's going on inside of it other than as just this magical machine that predicts things
And then two is how are people building with it and then importantly how can I
Build with it too if you are Developer and if you have cs50 background you should be able to pick things up and start building some great apps I've
I've already met some of the cs50 grads yesterday
And the things that they were doing were pretty amazing so
And talk about some of the theoretical background of GPT
Yeah so thank you Ted my name is song
Graduate student in the digital Humanities at Miguel
I studied literature and computer science in linguistics in the same breath
And I published some research over the last couple of years exploring what is possible
With language models
And culture in particular
My
Whatever of the presentation is to describe to you what is GPT
That's really difficult to explain in 15 minutes
And there are even a lot of things that we don't know but a good way to approach that is the first consider all the things
The people call GPT by
Play or descript
So you can call them large language models
You can call them Universal
From computer science you can say that that it is a generative AI
We know that they are neural networks we know that it is an artificial intelligence
The sun is a simulator of culture to others it just predicts text
You can plug in a pit of your essay get some feedback it's amazing for that
It's a Content generator people use it to do copywriting Jasper dot AI
Should I write etcetera
It's an agent so the really hot thing right now if you want to see it on Twitter Auto GPT baby AGI
People are giving these things tools
And letting them run a little bit free in the wild
Turn tracks with the world computers etc
The actual architecture
Is the Transformers so there's lots of ways to describe GPT
And any other one of them is a really perfectly adequate way
To begin the conversation
But for our purposes we can think of it as a large language model and more specifically a language model
Is a model of language
If you want me to tautology but really what it does is it produces a probability distribution over some vocabulary
So what is imagine that we had the task of
Predicting the next word
On the sequence I am so if I give
The words I am
What
All words in English
Is the next most likely word to follow
That at its very core is what GPT
Is trained to answer
And how it does it is it has a vocabulary of 50,000 words
And it knows roughly given the entire internet
Which words are likely to follow other words
Are those 50,000 in some sequence up to 2000 words up to 4000 up to 8,000 and now up
What's 32000354
So you give it a sequence here I am
And over the vocabulary of 50 words
It gives you the likelihood of every single word that follows so here it's
I am
Perhaps the word happiest
Fairly frequent so we'll get that high probability if we look at all words
All utterances of English
It might be I am sad maybe that's a little bit
What's probable I am school that really should be at the end cuz I don't think anybody would ever say that
I am Bjork that's a little bit
It's not very probable but it's less probable than happy sad but there's still some probability attached to it and when we say it's probable
Follows I am maybe like 5% of the time
Side Falls I am maybe 2% of the time
Or whatever so for every word
It tries to predict what the next word is
I cross 50,000 words and it gives every single one of those 50,000 words
Number that reflects how probable
And the Really magical thing that happens is you can generate new text
So if you give GPT I am and it products
Happy as being the most probable word over 50,000
You can then
Pendant to I am so now you say I am happy
And you feed it into the model again
Can you sample another word you feed it into the model again and again and again and again
There's lots of different ways that I am happy I am sad can go
And all the sudden you have a language model that can write essays that can talk
And a whole lot of things
Which is really unexpected and something that we didn't predict more even 5 years ago
So this is all relevant
And if we move on
As we scale up the model and we give it more compute in 2012 Alex that came out and we figured out we can give
We can run the model on gpus
So we can speed up the process
We can give the model lots of information downloaded from the internet
And it learns more and more and
And the probabilities that gives you
Get better as it sees more examples of English on the
So we have to train the model to be really large
Really wide
And with the trainer for a really long time
And as we do that the model gets more and more
And it also gets a little bit intelligent
And for reasons we don't understand
But they also the issue is that because it learns to replicate the internet
Knows how to speak in a lot of different genres
What is a text and a lot of different registers
If you begin the conversation like
Can you explain the moon landing to a 6 year old and a few sentences gpt-3
Is an example drawn from the instructor GPT paper from openai
Gpt-3 what I'm just been like
Okay so
You give me an example of explain the moon landing to a 6 year old I'm going to give you a whole bunch of similar things because those seem very likely to come
It doesn't necessarily understand that it's being asked a question has to respond with an
Gpt-3 did
Don't have the apparatus that interface for responding
The scientist
Open it I came up with the solution and that's
Let's give it a whole bunch of examples of question and answers
Such that we first trained on the internet
And then we train it with a whole bunch of questions and answers
Such that it has the knowledge of the internet
But really knows that it has to be answering questions
And that is when Chachi PT was born and that's when it gained 100 million users in one
Record at 20 million in one month
And for a lot of people
This thing is intelligent I can answer I can ask it questions and answers back we can work together to come to a solution
And that's because
Put a nose that predicts words
In the framework
I have a question and answer
So that's what a prompt is
That's what instruction tuning is that's a keyword
Are lhf is if you've ever seen that acronym reinforcement alignment
Human feedback
And all those combined means that
The bottles that are coming out today
The types of language protectors that are coming out today
Work to operate in a Q&A form
GPT 4 exclusively only has the a wine bottle
Available and this is a really
Solid foundation to build on
Because you can do all sorts of things you can ask
Can you do this for me can you do that for me
You might have seen that openai has allowed plug-in access to check CPT so I can access Wolfram
I can search the web I can search
I can do instacart for you
I can look up recipes
What's the model
Knows that not only it has to predict language but that it has
Solve the problem
And the problem here being
Give me a good answer to my question
It's suddenly able to interface with the world in a really solid way
And from there on there's been all sorts of tools that I build on
Does Q&A form that Chachi Beattie uses
You have
Auto GPT you have Lang chain you have
React there's a react paper where a lot of these come from and
Turn in the model into an agent with which to achieve
Any ambiguous goal is where the future is going
Good morning and this is all thanks to instruction tuning
What's that I think I will hand it off to Ted
Who will be giving a demo
Or something along those lines for how to
Use GPT as
All right so I'm a super applied guy
I kind of look at things and think okay how can I like to add this Lego add that Lego and clip them together
Together and build something with it
And right now you know if you look back in computer science history
When you look at the kinds of things that were being done in 1970
Right after Computing was invented the microprocessors were invented
People were doing research like how do I sort a list of numbers and that was meaningful work and importantly it was work that successful
Call to everybody because nobody knows what we can build with this new kind of oil this new kind of electricity this new kind of unit
Do you need a computation
We've created and anything was game and anybody could participate in that game to figure it out and I think one of the really
Play exciting things about GPT right now
Is yes in and of itself it's amazing
But then what could we do with it
If we call it over and over again if we build it into our algorithms and start to build it into broader software so the world really is
Yours to figure out this fundamental questions about what could you do if you could script computation itself over
Over and over again
In the way that computers can do not just talk with it but build things a topic
So we're hosting company we host apps and these are just some of the things that we see I'm going to show you demos of this
What is with code and try to explain some of the thought process but I wanted to give you a high level of overview of you've probably seen these on
Open Twitter but kind of win it all sorts out to the top these are some of the things that we're seeing built and deployed with language
What's the models today
Companionship
That's everything for my need a friend do I need a friend with a purpose I want to coach I want somebody to tell me go to the gym and do these
What size is I want somebody to help me study a foreign language
Question answering this is a big one this is everything from your Newsroom having a slack bot that helps assist you does
What is this article
Conform to the Style Guidelines of our Newsroom all the way through to I need help on my homework or hey I have
Play some questions that I want you to ask Wikipedia
Combine it with something else synthesized the answer and give it to me
Utility functions I would describe this as there's a large set of things for which
Human beings can do them if only or computers could do them if only they had access to language computation
An example of this would be
Read every tweet on Twitter tell me the ones I should read
That way I only get to read the ones that actually makes sense to me and I don't have to skim through the rest
Creativity
Image generation text generation storytelling proposing other ways to do things
And then these wild experiments and kind of baby AGI
In which the AI itself decides what to do in a self-directed so I'll show you examples of many of these and what the code looks like
And if I were you I would think about these as categories within which
To both think about what you might build
And then also seek out
Start a projects for how you might go about building them
Online
All right so I'm just going to dive straight into demos and code for some of these cuz I know that's what's interesting to see as fellow builders
With the high level diagram for some of these is to how it works
So approximately you can think of a companionship bot as a friend that has a purpose to you
And there are many ways to build all of these things but one of the ways you can build this is simply to wrap GPT
What language model
In an endpoint that additionally injection to the prompt
Some particular perspective or some particular goal that you want to use
It really is that easy in a way but it's also very hard because you need to iterate
Engineer the prompt
Consistently performs the way
You want it to perform
So a good example of this is something somebody built into hackathon yesterday and I just wanted to show you the project that they built it was
It was a mandarin idiom coach
And I'll show you what the code look like first I'll show you the Demo First
I think I already pulled it up
Here we go
So
The buddy that this person wanted to create was a friend that if you
Gave it a particular problem you were having
It would pick a Chinese idiom a four character chunk
That describe poetically like here's a particular way you could say this and it would tell it to her so that the
The person who built this was studying Chinese and she wanted to learn more about it so I might say something like I'm feeling
Very sad
If everything's up and running
It will
Generate one of these four character phrases
And it will respond to it
With an example now I don't know if this is correct or not so if somebody can call me out if this is actually incorrect you please please please
Call me
And it will then finish up with something encouraging say Hey you can do it I know this is hard keep going so let me show you how they built this
Yes and I
Pulled up
The code
Right here
So this was the
Particular starter replit
In the hackathon yesterday
You have a wrapper around GPT
And there's many things you could do but we're going to make it easy for you to do two things one of them
Is to inject some personality into the prom
And then the second is ADD tools that might go out and do a particular thing search the web
Or generate an image or add something to a database or fetch something from a database
So having done that
Now you have something more than GPT now you have GPT which we all know what it is and how we can interact with it
Added a particular lens through which it's talking to you and potentially some tools so this particular
Chinese tutor
All it took to build that was
Lines
So here's the question that I think is
Is frying the minds of everybody in the industry right now
So is this something that will all do casually and nobody really knows will we just all say in the future to the llm hey for the next
Next 5 minutes please talk like a teacher and maybe
But also definitely in the meantime and maybe in the future it makes sense to wrap up
I'm not just talking to GPT I have a whole Army of different buddies of different
Companions that I can talk to they're kind of human and kind of talk to me interactively
But because I preloaded them with hey by the way you particular
I want you to be kind helpful Chinese teacher that responds to every situation by explaining the chunk of its it
Speak in English and explain the children in its meaning
Then provide a note of encouragement about learning language
It's just adding something like that
Even if you're not programmer
You can just type deploy
And it'll pop it up to the web
It'll take it over to a telegram bot then you can even interact with hey
I'm feeling too busy
And interact with it over telegram over the web and this is the kind of thing that's now Within Reach
For everybody from cs101 grad sorry I'm using the general purpose framing
All the way through to Professionals in the industry that you can do just with a little bit of manipulation on top of
Conversation and intelligence
So companionship
Is is one of the first Common
Types of apps that we're seeing
Kind of app that we're seeing and this blew up if for those of you who are on
Kind of Twitter followers
This blew up
I think the last few months
Is question answering I want to unpack a couple of different ways this can work
Because I know many of you have probably already
I tried to build
Some of these kinds of apps there's a couple of different ways that it works
The general framework is
A user queries GPT and maybe it has general purpose knowledge maybe it doesn't have general purpose knowledge
But what you wanted to say
Play back to you
Is something specific about an article you wrote
Or something specific about
A particular set of documents from the United Nations on a particular topic
We've all interacted with these customer service spots
What kind of Smashing our heads on the keyboard as we do it
Pretty soon we're going to start to see very high fidelity Bots that interact with this comfortably
And this is approximately how to do it as an engineer so here's your game plan as an engineer
Step one
Take the documents
Do you want it to respond to
Step two
Cut them up now
For example
You could cut them up into clean sentences or clean paragraphs
Or semantically coherent
Honestly the way that most folks do it and this is a simplification that turns out tends to be just fine
Is you window you have a sliding window that goes over the document
And you just pull out fragments of text
Having pulled out those fragments of text you turn them into something called an embedding Vector it's an embedding vector
Is a list of numbers
That approximate some point of meaning
So you've already all dealt with embedding vectors yourself and regular life and the reason you have and I know you have is because everybody's order
Ordered food from Yelp before
You look at
What genre of restaurant is it is it in a pizza restaurant is it an Italian restaurant is it a Korean barbecue place
How many stars does it have one two three four five
You look at where is it so all of these you can think of as points in space dimensions in space Korean barbecue
Four stars
Near my house
It's a
Three number vect
That's all this
So this is a thousand number of vector or 10,000 number Vector different models produce different sized vectors
All it is
Is chunking pieces of text
Turning it into a vector that approximates meaning and then you put it in something called the vector database and a vector database is just a database
Pet stores numbers
But having that database
Now when I ask a question
I can search the database and I can say hey the question was what does cs50 teach
What pieces of text
In the database
Have vectors similar
To the question
What does cs50 teach
And there's all sorts of tricks and Empires being made on refinements of this General approach
But at the end you the developer
Model it simply as thus
And then when you have your query you embed it
You find the document fragments and then you put them into a prompt and now we're just back to the personality of the
Companionship
Now it's just a prompt
You're an expert in answering questions
Please answer
User provided question
Using Source documents
Results from the database
That's it
So after all of these Decades of engineering to these customer service spots it turns out with a couple of lines of code you can build
With the cs50 syllabus so we can
Pull that up
I added the PDF right here
Search the web for cs50 syllabus
What does PDF I put the URL in here
Piece of code deployed
That will now let me talk to it and I can say what will cs50 teach me
What's happening is exactly what that slide just showed you it takes that question what will cs50 teach me
It turns it into a vector
That Vector approximates without exactly representing
The meaning of that question
It looks into a vector database
Did steamship host
Fragments from that PDF
And then it pulls out a document and then passes it to a prompt that says
You're an expert at answering questions
Someone has asked you what does cs50 teach
Please answer it using only the source documents and Source materials I've provided now those Source materials Mater
Materials are dynamically loaded into the problem it's just basic prompt engineering and I want to keep harping back on to that
What's amazing about right now is builders
Is that so many things just boil down to very creative
Tactical
Rearrangement of prompts
And then using those over and over again in an algorithm and putting that into software so the result and again it could be lying it could be
Will you be making things up it could be hallucinating
Is cs50 will teach students how to think algorithmically and solve problems efficiently focusing on topics such as abstraction dot dot dot
And then it Returns the source document
So this is another big category
Of which there are tons
Potential applications
You can create arbitrarily many of these once its software because once its software
You can just repeat it
Over and over again so for your dorm for your Club
For your
For your Telegram
You can start to begin putting pieces of information
In and then responding to it and it doesn't have to be documents you can also load it straight
Into the prompt
I think I have it pulled up here
And if I don't I'll just skip it
One other way you can do question answering
I think it's healthy to always encourage the simplest possible approach to something
You don't need to engineer this giant system it's great to have a database it's great to use embeddings it's great to use this big approach it's
Play Fancy at Scales you can do a lot of things
But you can also get away with a lot
By just pushing it all into a prompt
Aspire to be lazy and I couldn't agree more
You as an engineer should want to set yourself up so that you can pursue the lazy path
Do something
So here's how you might do
The equivalent of a question answering system with a prompt alone let's say you have
30 friends
In each friend is good at a particular thing or you can you know
Is isomorphic too many other problems
You can simply just say hey I know certain things
Are users going to ask me something
How should we respond
And then you load that into an agent
That agent has access to GPT
You can ship deploy it
And now you've got a bot that you can connect to telegram you can connect to Slack
And that part
The variance of the model underneath
It will tend to answer with respect to this list and and the degree to which it tends to is to a certain extent
Something that both Industries working on to
Give everybody as a capacity
But also you doing prompt engineering to tighten up
The air bars
Just a few more examples
And then in about 8 minutes I'll turn it over to questions cuz I'm sure you got a lot about how to build things so just to give you
A sense of where we are
This is when I don't have a demo for you
But if you were to come to me and you were to say Ted
I want a weekend Hustle Man
What should I build
Holy Mol
There are a set of applications that I would describe as utility functions I don't like that name
Because it doesn't sound exciting and this is really exciting
Fruits that automate tasks
The required basic language understanding so examples for this are
Generate a unit test
I don't know how many of you
Have you ever been writing tests and you're just like oh come on
I can get through this
You're lucky individual
Looking up the documentation for a function rewriting a function making something conform to your company guidelines doing a brand check
All of these things are things that
Are kind of
Relatively context-free operations or scoped context operations on a piece of information
Information that requires linguistic understanding
Really you can think of them as something that is now available to you as a software Builder as a weekend project
Builder as a startup Builder
And you just have to build the interface around it
Presented to other people in a context in which its meaningful them for them to consume
And so the space of this
Is extraordinary I mean is the space of all human endeavor
Now with this new tool I think is the way to way to think about it people often joke about how
You don't want to start with a hammer
Because you want you want to start with the problem instead
And it's generally true but my God
We just got a really cool new hammer
And to a certain extent I would encourage you to at least casually on the weekends run around and hit stuff with it and see
What can happen from a builder's from a Tinkers from an experimental
Point of view
Creativity this is another huge mega app
No I'm primarily living the text world and so I'm going to talk about text-based things
I think so far this is mostly been growing in the imagery world because we're such visual creatures
Please and the images you can generate or just staggering
I certainly brings up a lot of questions to around IP and artistic style
Is approximately the following and the thing I want to
This is really the purpose of this slide is to touch on the importance of the domain knowledge
So many people
Approximately find the creative process as follow
Come up with a big idea
Over generate possibilities
Edit it down
What you over generated
Repeat
Right like anybody who's been a writer
And then you have to delete lots of it
This particular task is fantastic for AI one of the reasons it's fantastic for AI
Is because it allows the eye to be wrong you know you've pre-agreed you're going to delete lots of it and so if you pre agree hey I'm just going to
Generate five possibilities of the story I might tell five possibilities of the advertising headline
Five possibilities of what am I what I might write my thesis on
You are going to be the editor
Did stepson
And here's the thing that you really should bring to the table is don't think about this as a technical activity think about this
Is your opportunity not to put GPT in charge
Instead for you to grasp the steering wheel tighter
I think at least
In python or the language you're using to program
Because you have the domain knowledge
To wheel GPT in the generation of those so let me show you an example of what I mean by that
This is a
A cool app
Someone created for the writing Atlas project is a set
Short stories
And you can think of it as Goodreads for short stories
So you can go in here you can browse different stories
You can type in a story description that you like
And this is going to take about a minute to generate so I'm going to talk while it's generating
Is it searching through the collection of stories for similar stories and here's where the domain knowledge part comes in
Then it uses GPT
To look at what it was that you wanted
And use knowledge of how an editor how a Bookseller thinks to generate a set of suggestions specific
Specifically through the lens
Of that perspective with the goal of writing that beautiful handwritten note that we sometimes see in a local bookstore
Back on underneath
And so it doesn't just say hey you might like this here's a general purpose
Reason why you might like this but specifically
Here's why
You might like this with respect to what you gave it
It's either stalling out
Or it's taking a long time oh there we go
So here's a suggestions
In particular these things these are things that only a human could know at least for now
Two humans specifically
The human who said they wanted to read a story that's the text that came in
And then the human who added domain knowledge
Descriptive sequence of interactions with the language model
So that you could provide very targeted reasoning
Over something that was informed by that domain knowledge
Utility
Apps bring your bring your domain knowledge
Looks and code cuz I think it's it's it's useful to see how simple and accessible this is
This is really
Like a particular location
Well here's the prompt that did that is an open source project
Interested in
Here's the audience here's a couple of examples of why might people like a particular thing in terms of audience it's just another prompt
And if you go down here and look at how it was done
Suggesting the story is what is this line 174 to line 203 it really is and and again
It's really just
What 20 outlines of Step 1
Search in the database for similar stories
Step two
Given that I have similar stories pull out the data
Step 3
With my domain knowledge in Python
Now run these prompts
Step four prepare that into an output so the thing we're scripting itself
Is some approximation of
Is human cognition
If you're willing to go there metaphorically we're not you know we're not sure I'm not going to weigh in on where we are on the is openai
A life form
Argument
All right one kind of really far out there thing and then I'll
Tied up for questions cuz I know there's probably a lot and I also want to make sure you get
Great pizza in your bellies
And that is a baby AGI
Auto GPT is what you might have heard them called on Twitter I think of them as multi-step planning bots so everything I showed
Why are you so far
Was approximately one shot interactions with GPT
So this is the user says they want something
And then either python mediates interactions with GPT
GPT itself
Does some things with the inflection of a personality that you've added from some prompt engineering
Really useful
Pretty easy to control if you want to go to production if you want to build a weekend project if you want to build a company that's a great way to do it
Right now
This is wild and if you haven't seen this stuff on Twitter I would definitely recommend going to search for it
This is what happens
If you put GPT in a for Loop
If you let GPT talk to itself and then tell itself what to do
It's an emergent Behavior
It starts with a few simple steps the Conway's Game of Life
Elements of reality turn out to be math equations that fit on a t-shirt
This is approximately
Step one take a human objective
Step two
Your first task
Is to write yourself a list of steps and here's the critical part
Repeat
Now do the list of steps now you have to embody your agent with the ability to do things so it's really
You're the only limited to do what you give it the tools to do
And what has the skills to do
So obviously this is still very much
A set of experiments that are running right now and and but it's something that will see unfold over the coming years and this is the scenario in which
Play python stops becoming so important because we've given it the ability to actually self-direct
What it's doing
And then it finally gives you
Engineering which is wild
How little code this is let me show you what
Baby AGI looks like
So here is
Baby AGI that you can connect to Telegram
And this is an agent that has two tools so I haven't explained to you what an agent is I haven't explained to you what tools are I'll give you
Give me a quick one sentence description in agent
Is just a word to mean
GPT
Plus some bigger body in which it's living maybe that body has a personality maybe has tools maybe it has python mediating
Kids experience with other
Tools are simply
Ways in which the agent can choose to do things like imagine if GPT could say order a pizza
And instead of you seeing the text order a pizza that caused the pizza to be ordered that's a tool
To-do list one tool is
Do a search on the web
And then down here
It has a prompt saying hey your goal is to build a task list and then do that task list
And then this is just placed into a harness
It does it over and over again so after the next task
Turn on cue the results of that task
And keep it going
You get this kickstarted Loop
We're essentially you Kickstart it
And then the agent is talking to itself
Stop talking to yourself
So this unless I'm wrong I don't think this is yet reached production in terms of what we're seeing in the field of how people are deploying
Keep playing software
But if you want to dive into sort of the wildest part of experimentation this is definitely one of the places you can start
All you have to do
Is download one of the starter projects for it
And you can kind of see right in the prompting here's how you kick start that process
Obliteration
All right so I know that was super high level
I hope it was useful
I think from the field from the bottoms up what we're seeing and what people are building and the high level categories
Of apps that people are making
All of these apps are apps that are within reach to everybody which is really really exciting
And there's a I suggest Twitter is a great place to hang out and build things
There's a lot of AI builders on Twitter publishing
And if I think we got a couple minutes before Pizza is arriving maybe 10 minutes keep on going
Kick it to that cuz I'm sure there's some
Questions that you all have I guess I need a little early
The question was how is approximately how do you manage the hallucination problem if you give it a physics
Lecture and you ask it a question
On the one hand it appears to be answering you correctly
On the other hand it appears to be wrong to an expert's i
40% of the time 70 of the time 10 of the time
It's a huge problem
And then what are some ways is developers practically you can use to mitigate that
I'll get an answer so you may have some specific things too so one high level answer is
The same thing that makes these things capable of synthesizing information is part of the reason why it hallucinates for you so it's hard to have
Have your cake and eat it too to a certain extent
So this is part of the game in fact humans do it too
Make people talk about you know just folks who kind of are too aggressive in their assumptions about knowledge I can't remember the name for
Some things you can do
Are kind of a range of activities depending on how much money you're willing to spend how much technical expertise you have that can range from fine-tuning a model
To practically I'm in the applied world so I'm very much in the world of duct tape and sort of how developers get stuff done so
Giving an example
Tends to work for a cute things if it's behaving in wild ways
Is the more examples you give it
That's not going to solve the domain of all of physics
So for the domain of all the physics I'm going to I'm going to bail and give it to you cuz I think you are far more equipped than me to speak on that sure so
The bottle doesn't have
A ground TR
It doesn't know anything any sense of meeting that is derived from the training process
Is purely out of
Differentiation one word is not another word words are not used
The same contact
It understands everything only through examples given through language it's like someone who learned English
Or how to speak
But they grew up in a featureless gray room that never seen the outside world they have nothing to rest on that tells them that something is
True and something is not true
So from the models perspective everything that it says
It's true it's trying its best to give you the best answer possible and if
Lying a little bit or conflating two different topics is the best way to achieve that then it will decide to do so
It's a part of the architecture we can't get around it
There are a number of cheap tricks
That surprisingly get it to confabulate her hallucinate less one of them includes recently there was a paper that's a little funny
If you get it to pretend
My best guess is
That will actually improve
Or reduce hallucinations by about 80%
But we're not quite sure what that is
Turn on to what time was saying a few cheap things you can do include
Google or Bing as in bing chai what they're doing and it says this information
Make sure its own responses good if you've ever had such a BT generate a program
I think there's a mistake
Austin it will locate the mistake itself
Why I didn't produce the right answer at the very beginning we're still not sure
But we're moving in the direction of reducing hallucinations not with respect
Physics
You're going to have to give it an external database
To restaurant because internally
For really really
Domain specific knowledge it's not going to
B
Deterministic as one would like these things work and continuous spaces these things
They don't know what is wrong what is true
And as a result
Striving at reducing hallucinations actually really and giving it more AB
One of the ways to that I mean I'm a simple guy like I tend to think that
All of the world tends to be just a few things repeated over and over again
Keep playing sports
And we're not right all the time even when we aspire to be
And so we have systems that we've developed as humans to deal with
Things that may be wrong
So you know human number one proposes an answer
Human number two checks their work
Human number three provides the final sign-off this is really common anybody who's worked in a company has seen this in practice
The interesting thing about the state of software right now
We tend to be in this mode in which we're just talking to GPT is one entity
But once we start thinking in terms of teams
Is so to speak
Where each team member is its own agent with its own set of objectives and skills
I suspect we're going to start seeing a programming model in which the way to solve this might not necessarily be
Make a single brain smarter
But instead be draw upon the collective intelligence of multiple software agents
Each playing a row
And and I think that that
Would certainly follow the human pattern of how we deal
To give an analogy space shuttles
Things that go into space spacecraft
They have to be
Good if they're not good people die they have
No no margin for error at all
As a result we over-engineering those systems
Most spacecraft have three computers and they all have to agree in unison
Turn on a particular step to go forward
One does not agree
Then they recalculate the recalculate the recalculate until they arrive at something
Did the good thing is that hallucinations
Are generally not a systemic problem in terms of its knowledge
It's often a one-off
What's the model of something tripped it up and it just produced
Working in unison
That will generally speaking improve your
Sure I'm going to give you what might be an unsatisfying answer which is it tends to work
But I think we know why it tends to work and again it's because these language models approximate how we talk to each other
So if I were to say to you hey help me out I need you to mock interview me
That's a direct statement I can make that kicks you into a certain mode of interaction
Or if I say to you help me out
I'm trying to apologize to my wife
She's really mad at me can you role play with me
Play that kicks you into another motive interaction and and so it's really just a shorthand that people have found to kick the
Agent in to kick the llm into a certain mode of interaction
The tends to work in the way that I as a software developer
I'm hoping it would work
Being in the digital Humanities that I am I like to think of it as a narrative a narrative will
A few different characters talking to each other
The rules are clearly defined
Two people are not the same
This interaction with GPT it assumes a personality it can simulate personalities
Is it itself is not cautious in any way but it can certainly
Predict what a conscious being would react like in a particular situation so when we're going you are
It is
Drawing of that personality and talking as long as that person
Because it is it is like completing a transcript or completing a story
In which that character is present
And interacting
I think we got about 5 minutes until the pizza outside
So GPT for One gpc4 release back in
March I think it was
It was passing Elsa
That's one of the weird things is that
If you pay for Chachi PT they give you access to the better model
What are the interesting things with it is prompting it's so finicky
It's very sensitive to the way that you prompt
The earlier on when gpt-3 came out some people were going look I can pass literacy tests or no it can't pass
Call Teresita
And the people who are pro or anti GPT would be like
I modified The Prompt a little bit suddenly I can suddenly I can't
These things are not conscious
The ability to reason is like an alien
They're not us they don't think like people they're not human
But they certainly are capable
Of passing some things empirically which demonstrates some sort of
Rational or logic within the model
But we're still slowly figuring out
What exactly the right approach
Companies on top of us who that's their primary product
The the value that it adds is like any company I mean it's you know what is the Y combinator
Is there a motto make something people want I mean
I wouldn't think of this as GPT inherently provides value
GPT for prioritized access
Where your product might be
Is how you take that and combined it
Your data somebody else's data some domain knowledge some interface
That then helps apply it to something
It is two things are both true there are a lot of experiments going on right now
Both for fun and people trying to figure out where the economic value is
Companies that are 100% supported by applying this
I I think that it is likely
That today we call this GPT and today we call these flms and tomorrow it will just
Slide into The Ether imagine what the imagine what the progression is going to be today there's one of these that the people are primarily
Top
Tomorrow we can expect
That there will be many of them
And the day after that we can expect they're going to be on our phones and they're not even going to be connected to the internet
And for that reason I think that like today we don't call our software microprocessor tools or
Is microprocessor apps like the processor just exists
I think that one useful Model 5 years
10 years out
Is to even if it's only metaphorically true and not literally true
I think it's useful to think of this as a second processor we have this before with with with floating point
What processors in graphic scope processors
It's useful to think of the trajectory of this as just another thing that computers to do can do and will be incorporated
Put it into absolutely everything
Hence the term Foundation model which
It's hard to get it to do that reliably it's incredibly useful to get it to do reliable so some tricks you can use
You can give examples
You can just ask it directly
Those are two common tricks
And and look at the prompts that others have used to work I mean there's a lot of art to finding the right prompt right now
A lot of it is Magic incantation
Another thing you can do is post-process it
So that you can do some checking and you can have a happy path in which it's a one shot and you get your answer and then a sad path
Can which maybe you fall back on other prompts so then you're going for the diversity of approach where
It's it's fast by default
It's slow but ultimately converging upon higher likelihood of success if it fails
Instruction tuning style models
Which are more likely to respond with the computer possible
That's a great question so the question was and I apologize I just realized we haven't been repeating all the questions for the the YouTube listeners so I'm sorry for the focus on
Open YouTube if you weren't able to hear some of the questions
The question was what are the Privacy implications of some of these prompts if one of the messages is so much depends upon your prompt
In the fine tuning of this prompt what does that mean
With respect to my IP maybe the prompt is my business
I can't offer you the exact answer but I can paint for you what approximately the landscape looks like so
In all of software and so too with AI
What we see is there the SAS companies where you're using somebody else's API and you're trusting that their terms and service
This will be upheld
There's the set of companies in which they provide a model for hosting on one of the big cloud providers
And this is a version of the same thing but I think with slightly different mechanics this tends to be thought of as the Enterprise version of software
And by and large the industry has moved over the past 20 years from running my own servers to trusting that Microsoft or Amazon or Google can
Run servers for me and they say it's my private server even though I know they're running it
And I'm okay with that
With their own version of
How hard are going to do these where you'll have the SAS version
And then there's a third version that I think we haven't yet seen practically emerged but this would be the the maximalist I want to make sure my
IP is maximally safe version of events in which you are running your own machines you are running your own models
And then the question is
Is the open source and or privately available version of the model
As good as the publicly hosted one and does that matter to me
And the answer is right now realistically it probably matters a lot
In the fullness of time you can think of any one particular task you need to achieve is requiring some fixed point of
Intelligence to achieve
The privately obtainable versions of these models will cross that threshold
And with respect to that one task
Ask ya sure use the open source version run it on your own machine
But will also see the SAS intelligence
Get smarter it'll probably stay ahead
And then your question is well which one do I care more about
Do I want like the better aggregate intelligence or is my task somewhat fixed point and I can just use the open source available
Cross the threshold
So to answer your question specifically
Yes
You might be glad to know if Chachi PT recently updated their privacy policy to not use prompts for the training process
Put up until now everything went back into the bin to be trained
And that's just
So I think Pizza